



Wondimu Bantihun Demlew

O Home: Maraki, 6200, Gondar, Ethiopia

Email: wondimubantihun2005@gmail.com Phone: (+251) 934596125

in LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/wonde-man-tube-2a80791bb

Gender: Male Date of birth: 19/06/1993 Nationality: Ethiopian

ABOUT MYSELF

I am Wondimu Bantihun, an experienced lecturer and researcher with a strong background in electrical and computer engineering. I earned my BSc degree in Electrical and Computer Engineering from the University of Gondar in 2017 and my MSc degree in Computer Engineering from Bahir Dar Institute of Technology in 2022. Since 2018, I have been teaching at the University of Gondar, specializing in artificial intelligence, machine learning with Python, emerging technologies, data structures, robotics, and industrial automation. Beyond academia, I am actively involved in research and community service projects.

In addition to my teaching and research experience, I am a skilled full-stack developer with expertise in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Java, Python, and PHP. My long-term goal is to establish an Al-driven lab center focused on advancing key sectors such as healthcare, agriculture, and education.

WORK EXPERIENCE

[24/08/2022 - Current] Lecturer in Electrical and Computer Engineering

Institute of Technology, University of Gondar

City: Gondar | Country: Ethiopia

Main Tasks:

- prepare and deliver lectures, tutorials, and seminars.
- advising of undergraduate students project.
- research and community service

[02/03/2018 - 28/09/2019] Assistance Lecturer in Electrical and Computer Engineering

Institute of Technology, University of Gondar

City: Gondar | Country: Ethiopia

Main Tasks:

- assist in teaching undergraduate courses.
- · developing course materials, including course syllabi, assignments, and assessments.
- Provide guidance to students and support their learning.

EDUCATION AND TRAIN-ING

[22/12/2022 - 28/12/2023] Hihger Diploma Programme (HDP) in Teaching Methods

University of Gondar (UoG) https://www.uog.edu.et

Address: Maraki 196, Gondar, Ethiopia | **Field(s) of study:** Education

Main subject/occupational skills covered:

· Pedagogical knowledge, classroom management, lesson planning, assessment and evaluation, communication skills, reflective practice, collaboration, cultural competence, student engagement, adaptability, classroom leadership, critical thinking and problem solving, ethical and professional conduct, and action research skills.

[29/09/2019 - 23/08/2022] **MSc. in Computer Engineering**

Bahir Dar Institute of Technology- Bahir Dar University www.bit.bdu.edu.et

Address: poly 26, Bahir Dar, Ethiopia | Final grade: 3.77 | Thesis: Designing Energy-Efficient Clustering and Multi-hop Routing Using a Hybrid Optimization GAC-SSA Algorithm for WSNs.

Main Subject covered:

· Advanced Computer Networks, Advanced Operating System, Advanced Computer Architecture, Advanced Embedded System, Advanced Distributed Systems, Computer and Network Security, Advanced VLSI Design, Wireless Network and Mobile Computing, Computer Vision, Machine Learning, Research Methods, and MSc. Thesis.

[28/09/2012 - 08/07/2017] BSc in Electrical and Computer Engineering (Computer Stream)

University of Gondar http://www.uog.edu.et

City: Gondar | Country: Ethiopia | | Final grade: 3.50/4.0 | Thesis: Microcontroller Based Car Parking System for University of Gondar

Main subjects/occupational skills covered:

• Introduction to Engineering Profession, Introduction to Power System, Introduction to Control System, Industrial Automation, Embedded Systems, Introduction to Robotics, Fundamental of Electrical Engineering, Electrical Materials and Technology, Introduction to Electrical Machines, Engineering Mechanics, Electrical Measurement and Instrumentation, Applied Mathematics (I,III), Applied Engineering Mathematics II., Introduction to Computing (C++), Engineering Themodynamics, Applied Electronics, Computational Methods, Probability and Random Process, Electromagnetic Fields, Signals and System Analysis, Object-Oriented Programming (java), Network Analysis and Synthesis, Digital Logic Design, Digital Signal Processing, Communicative english, Basic Writing Skill etc.

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s): Amharic

Other language(s):

English

LISTENING B2 READING C2 WRITING C1

SPOKEN PRODUCTION B1 SPOKEN INTERACTION B1

French

LISTENING A1 READING A1 WRITING A1

SPOKEN PRODUCTION A1 SPOKEN INTERACTION A1

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user - B1 and B2: Independent user - C1 and C2: Proficient user

DIGITAL SKILLS

My Digital Skills

Programming Languages - C,C++, |ava,HTML and MS SQL server | MS Office (Word, Excel-VBA, Power Point) | Google (Google Meet, Google Docs, Google Clasroom, Google Forms, Google Drive, Google Slide) | Social Media / Social Network | Video Conferencing (Zoom, Teams, Skype, Webex) - Advanced | Social Media including Facebook, WhatsApp and Twitter

VOLUNTEERING

[09/06/2022 - Current] Menna elderly and mentally challenging support center Gondar, Ethiopia

Menna elderly and mentally challenging support center, is a non-profit organization that was founded in 2014 by university students. Currently, this organization provides full retirement and support services for the poor, elderly, and mentally challenged people who don't have someone to look after or support them. The organization provides shelter, food, clothing, and medical support for the elderly and mentally challenged people, inside or outside the care center.

main achievement: participate in fund-raising activities to generate financial support; make a donation of 100 ETB per month; and make a skill-based contribution like developing a website for the organization; distribute meals and closes collected from the university students and others;

RECOMMENDATIONS

Name: Lake Fereaw Atnafu Lecturer, Electrical and Computer Engineering, Institute of Technology ,University of Gondar

I knew Mr. Wondimu Bantihun in the department of Electrical and Computer Engineering at the University of Gondar when I taught him object-oriented programming and data structure at the undergraduate level. I was also his thesis advisor for the final year research project titled "Microcontroller-Based Car Parking System for University of Gondar." Currently, he is my colleague and has various responsibilities. I want to emphasize that he is capable of participating in and excelling in master's and other advanced academic programs, and I have no doubt that he will play a great role in his nation's development.

Phone number: (+251) 985072832 | E-mail: lake.fereaw@uog.edu.et